all right
[Music]
conventional wisdom has it that over the
last 50 years sleep duration has
declined in parallel with the increasing
prevalence of obesity suggesting that an
epidemic of sleep loss is associated
with the epidemic of weight gain now we
have triple digit streaming TV channels
smartphones and tablets to keep us
entertained well into the night the
hurry and excitement of Modern Life is
quite correctly held to be responsible
for much of the insomnia concluded one
medical journal editorial but that was
an editorial published in
1894 are we really sleeping that much
less
it's 1905 sleep duration in children and
Adolescence has declined by a little
over an hour a night however child labor
was an outlawed until 1938 though and so
part of the explanation may be due to
the exhaustion of sweating it out in the
mines farms and factories in the early
part of the last century since 1970
youth sleep duration has only declined
about 15 minutes per night and it's not
clear sleep duration in adults has
changed much at all based on 168 studies
of objective measurements of sleep
duration instead of just self-report
sleep duration in adults
objective Total Sleep Time hasn't
changed much since 1960. since 2003
average sleep duration in the United
States may have even gone up now of
course just because we don't have
evidence that there's been a growing
epidemic of sleep deprivation that
doesn't necessarily mean we're getting
enough sleep maybe we weren't getting
enough sleep 50 years ago either or
since Edison's light bulbs or since
candles were invented 5 000 years ago
how might we determine the optimal sleep
duration one way would be to study
millions of people and see how many
hours a night is associated with the
longest lifespan
sleep is a great mystery a trait shared
across animal species sleep must be of
vital importance to survive natural
selection pressures to eliminate such a
vulnerable state indeed cringe-worthy
experiments have shown that keeping
animals awake long enough is fatal
within 11 to 32 days
one of the functions of sleep that has
been elucidated in recent years is the
clearance of toxic waste substances that
build up during the day through a newly
discovered drainage system in the brain
this could help explain why those who
routinely get less than seven hours of
sleep at night may be an increased risk
of developing cognitive disorders such
as dementia even a single all-nighter
can cause a significant increase in beta
amyloid accumulation in critical brain
areas a gummy substance implicated in
the development of Alzheimer's disease
the lowest risk for developing cognitive
impairment was found for those getting
seven to eight hours of sleep at night
which is the same optimal Range found
for diabetes risk based on 36 studies
following more than a million people The
increased risk associated with getting
only six hours a night compared to seven
or eight is comparable to the increase
in diabetes risk linked to physical
inactivity
for death from all causes combined
there's been more than 50 studies
following hundreds of thousands of
people for up to 34 years sleeping too
short and too long are both associated
with cutting one's life short with the
apparent sweet spot at seven hours a
night seven hours may seem short but
that may actually be what's natural for
our species scientists studied three
isolated pre-industrial societies across
two continents and found a surprising
uniformity despite no electric lighting
or gadgets they stayed up until about
three hours after Sunset and then
typically Rose Before Dawn accumulating
about a solid six and a half hours of
sleep out of about seven and a half
hours in quote-unquote bed
a mechanism by which excess sleep might
be harmful remains Elusive and so the
association between increased risk of
death and disease and sleeping nine or
more hours a night has been largely
dismissed as implausible maybe it's
reverse causation sickness leading to
more time in bed instead of Vice Versa
or confounding factors such as
employment status after all who gets to
sleep in those without a job to get to
however there is experimental evidence
showing negative health effects from
insufficient sleep so in terms of
sleeping in The Sweet Spot aim for at
least seven hours of regular sleep a day
foreign